<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vult Modules Free</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:04:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/free/</guid>
      <description>The Free (VultModulesFree) package contains a subset of the Premium (VultModules) modules.
Differences with the Premium (VultModules) version  Alternative models for Lateralus and Tangents and disabled.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vult Mysteries</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/mysteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:04:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/mysteries/</guid>
      <description>Vult Mysteries is a collection modules aimed to explore crazy ideas and turn them into usable modules (if possible).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vult Modules Premium</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/premium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:04:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/premium/</guid>
      <description>The Premium package (VultModules) contains all the Free modules plus some of the most complex modules I have developed.
Differences with the Free (VultModulesFree) version  Six extra modules: Ferox, Flame, Noxious, Nurage, Rescomb 2 and Vortex. Three extra filter modules shown as alternative models for Lateralus and Tangents. Polyphonic versions of all Free modules  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vult Compacts</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/compacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:04:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/compacts/</guid>
      <description>Compacts (VultCompacts) is Vult&amp;rsquo;s second collection of modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferox</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/ferox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:57:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/ferox/</guid>
      <description>Ferox is based on the ingenious CMOS filter design. The CMOS filter uses an digital inverter chip to replace operational amplifiers. The result filter full of character, distorted and aggressive. Ferox can transform the simplest waveforms into completely new sound. In some cases it will make you doubt that it is a filter at all.
Documentation  Cutoff: this is the main knob in a filter. It defines the frequency at which the filter starts taking action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freak</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:57:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/freak/</guid>
      <description>The Freak! is a collection of all the Vult filters into a single module (in stereo). The Freak! is part of the Vult Compacts package.
The Freak! has advantages and disadvantages over the individual filters. For example, it can process signals in stereo, but lacks the flexibility of having the individual inputs and outputs of the different filter modes.
Documentation  Cutoff: this is the main knob in a filter. It defines the frequency at which the filter starts taking action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freak-HW</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/freak-hw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:57:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/freak-hw/</guid>
      <description>This version of Freak is a clone of the actual hardware module. This module simulates as close as possible all the aspects of the original hardware module. It is a simulator that runs the same code as the hardware module.
You can find the full manual in the main product page https://www.vult-dsp.com/freak
Videos </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nurage</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/nurage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:57:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/nurage/</guid>
      <description>Nurage was modeled after a modded version of the most famous Low Pass Gate. Nurage comprises Vult&amp;rsquo;s own (very detailed) model of the vactrol control and the filter.
This module can be used to produce very natural sounding percussion sounds. It provides the possibility to enable or disable the Vactrol, the VCA and the possibility of using the module as stereo filter.
Documentation The Cutoff, Resonance and Drive knobs affect both filters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vraids</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vraids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:57:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vraids/</guid>
      <description>Vraids is a module that simulates the alternative firmware available for the Freak hardware module. This meas that, if you have a Freak hardware, you can change the full behavior by uploading the Vraids firmware.
You can find the full manual in the main product page https://www.vult-dsp.com/freak
Videos </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/about/</guid>
      <description>Vult is the side project of Dr. Leonardo Laguna Ruiz.
After more than 10 years developing scientific software, he decided to apply all his knowledge in electronics, mathematical modelling and simulation to his favorite hobby: Music Technology. ​
Currently, Leonardo still works developing the simulation core of Wolfram SystemModeler and runs Vult with the help of his family and friends.
​ Over the years, many people have helped with testing, design and ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basal</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/basal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/basal/</guid>
      <description>Basal is a easy to use and nice sounding oscillator. It&amp;rsquo;s specifically designed for creating smooth sounds with low harmonic content. Basal features a self modulation technique that acts when the oscillator is moved.
Documentation  Tune: offsets the V/OCT input one octave up or down. Oct: offsets the V/OCT input three octaves up and down. Mod 1: creates overtones by distorting the phase of the main oscillator (-10V to +10V).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blank Panels</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/panels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/panels/</guid>
      <description>The blank panels are an exclusive set of modules for the people that has the paid version. The only function of these panels is to make your Rack look more beautiful by adding the Vult logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bleak</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/bleak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/bleak/</guid>
      <description>Bleak is a virtual analog oscillator with zero aliassing that provides very easy to use controls to help you transform the waves. Bleak provides three waveforms that can be morphed and PW modulated.
Documentation  Tune: offsets the V/OCT input one octave up or down. Oct: offsets the V/OCT input three octaves up and down. PW: defines the pulse-with of the waves. In the case of saw and triangle an equivalent effect of the wave is provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boomstick</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/boomstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/boomstick/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bypass</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/bypass/</guid>
      <description>Bypass (or Util-Bypass) provides an easy way to engage or disengage an audio effect. Bypass can be used to convert any effect into a stompbox like effect allowing to turn it on or off with the press of a pedal.
Documentation  Status: displays if the effect is engaged (light on) or disengaged (light off). This is so far the only light that you&amp;rsquo;ll find in any Vult module. Mode: defines how the Bypass behaves when the gate signal fires or the manual button are pressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caudal</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/caudal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/caudal/</guid>
      <description>Caudal is a chaotic source that is based on the model of a multi segment pendulum (see the video below). The core of Caudal is a detailed simulation of the pendulum system from which we can get measurements like the angular velocities and positions of the segments. These measures produces very natural oscillations that are interrelated due to the nature of the system.
I made the original model using SystemModeler and later applied manual optimizations to improve the performance and being able of running it in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debriatus</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/debriatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/debriatus/</guid>
      <description>Debriatus is a chain of distortion effects that can be controlled with CV. A little bit of all the effect can turn a boring sine wave into a wave full of character.
Documentation  Fold: in this mode transforms the input signal by &amp;ldquo;folding&amp;rdquo; it within a defined threshold. It provides a sound that resembles adding extra harmonics to the signal. Crush: Bit crusher. Reduces the number of bits used to represent the signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decline</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/decline/</guid>
      <description>Decline is a simple and efficient equalizer. It consist of two peak filters, one high shelf and one low shelf.
Documentation All equalizers have a at least two controls: one for the Frequency and one for the Gain. The peak equalizers include an extra Q control. The actual values of the frequencies and gains can bee seed by enabling the tooltip values.
 Freq: defines the operating frequency of the equalizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disjoint</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/disjoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/disjoint/</guid>
      <description>Documentation not yet available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dopamine</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/dopamine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/dopamine/</guid>
      <description>Dopamine is based on the idea that, every time we tell one of our memories our brain reconstructs the events rather than just recalling them. Our brain is an imperfect medium of storage where our memories can get confused or we can forget parts of the story.
Dopamine simulates this behavior by using different layers of virtual neurons. These neurons will try to store CV and Gate information and they will recall it as best as they can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/download/</guid>
      <description>All modules are available in the VCV Rack store.
The modules can be found in three packages:
 Free Version - VultModulesFree Premium - VultModules Compacts - VultCompacts  You can find the details in the following links:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feigen</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/feigen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/feigen/</guid>
      <description>Feigen is a quasi-chaotic voltage source that has a few interesting properties for music. On it&amp;rsquo;s core lies the Logistic Map equation which is capable of producing periodic and chaotic patterns depending on it&amp;rsquo;s settings. Additionally, the generated sequences can be controlled by selecting the initial state (the Root) and resetting the module.
Control Description Main controls  Growth: It defines the characteristics of the generated voltages. When set full CCW, the module will generate oscillate producing two values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flame</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/flame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/flame/</guid>
      <description>Flame is a simulation of three different distortion pedals and three tone circuits.
Over the years, I have build many distortion pedals based on known designs. Often times I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the exact components that the pedal required and I just used what I had. I built three different distortion circuits that I intended to use in my real eurorack and I based Flame on those three modules.
Documentation Each of the following controls provides an attenuverter and a CV input to modulate them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/flux/</guid>
      <description>Flux is a module that was specifically designed to work with Caudal. Flux provides the following functions:
 Attenuation and offsetting Sample &amp;amp; Hold Clocked comparison Linear and exponential signal follower (slew limiter) Envelope follower  Flux provides 4 similar channels and the classical Vult modulation section that allows you to control all parameters.
Documentation  Mode:  S&amp;amp;H: Sample and hold. Keeps the immediate value of the input on every rising edge of the clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperPower</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/hyperpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/hyperpower/</guid>
      <description>This is a silly module I sent as gratitude to the people that donated money. Now it comes as part of the paid package.
HyperPower provides the best power supply in the market for your VCV Rack. If you love your Vult modules don’t let them get damaged; this is the recommended power supply. Using HyperPower will allow you using as many modules as your computer can handle.
Specifications:
 Outputs: -12, +12, +5 V, variable output -12 V to 12 V Output power: Infinite Efficiency: 100 % Output ripple: 0 %  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incubus</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/incubus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/incubus/</guid>
      <description>Incubus is full synthesizer in a single module. It&amp;rsquo;s assembled out of pieces of other modules like Vessek, Noxious, Caudal.
Full documentation coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julste</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/julste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/julste/</guid>
      <description>Julste is the only model that I haven&amp;rsquo;t developed by myself. When I started doing research on low pass gates I came across the paper &amp;ldquo;A DIGITAL MODEL OF THE BUCHLA LOWPASS-GATE&amp;rdquo; by Julian Parker and Stefano D’Angelo. They did all the hard job modeling it, and I rewrote the code in the Vult language and created the module.
The module has a few extensions to the original model, like controls to process the gate input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knobs</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/knobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/knobs/</guid>
      <description>Knobs (or Util-Knobs) is a simple but very handy utility. Knobs features four inputs with attenuverters and a big offset knob. Knobs can be used for many purposes, for example: to blend many modulation signals and send them to a single destination, as audio mixer, as constant voltage output.
Documentation Knobs contains two similar sections. Most of the elements in the interface are unlabeled.
 Mode: defines how the big knob behaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knock</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/knock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/knock/</guid>
      <description>Knock is a modern take on a classic analog bass drum. It features a hybrid engine capable producing a wide variety of drum sounds. The Stress input allows for further shaping of the sound by using a vactrol model to control the envelope.
Knock is split in two sections: the oscillator and noise synthesizers. The oscillator section is analog modeled while the noise is a special oscillator capable of producing many kinds of clicking sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lapsus</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/lapsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/lapsus/</guid>
      <description>The manual is almost done&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lateralus</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/lateralus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/lateralus/</guid>
      <description>Lateralus is ladder filter which is the same structure that a very famous inventor created for his synthesizers. Lateralus is a detailed simulation model based on my own diode ladder filter.
The paid version of Lateralus has two implementations. Each implementation is based on a different simulation model that I have developed.
Some of the &amp;ldquo;weird&amp;rdquo; behaviors of the real filter were intentionally not reproduced in order to bring a more controllable filter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leakage</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/leakage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/leakage/</guid>
      <description>Leakage is a multi purpose voltage processor. It&amp;rsquo;s a single line of Flux but with a few improvements. It can be used as:
 Gain control Offset Sample and hold Slew limiter (linear and exponential) Envelope follower Noise source Gate  Documentation  Range: Attenuates/amplifies the input signal (or noise) from 0x to 2x. Offset: Adds a constant voltage to the input signal from -5V to 5V. Follower:  Lin: The output signal will approach the input signal linearly at a rate defined by the Rate knob.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nopskate</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/nopskate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/nopskate/</guid>
      <description>Nopskate is my take on the classic flip-flop octaver pedal but adapted to VCV Rack. Given any input signal, Nopskate will generate signals that are one and two octaves below the input signal. The generated signals can be added or multiplied (AM) to the original. These two ways of blending the generated signal can transform a simple input signal into a richer wave.
Nopskate is based on a circuit I made many years ago which was a failed attempt to clone the octaver guitar pedal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noxious</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/noxious/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/noxious/</guid>
      <description>Noxious is a digital oscillator and LFO based on Frequency and Phase modulation techniques. The idea for Noxious was to create an oscillator that captures the crazy and experimental nature of FM and PM but at the same time making easy to obtain usable results. Noxious can create from soft and cheesy sounds to very abrasive and distorted screams. In LFO mode can create quasi-chaotic signals.
Noxious is unpredictable but controllable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quincunx</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/quincunx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/quincunx/</guid>
      <description>Quincunx is based on the machine with the same name, also known as &amp;ldquo;bean machine&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Galton board&amp;rdquo;. Quincunx simulates this machine but adds some special features that make it more usable to generate voltages and pulses.
Basic Use Connect a clock signal to the input CLK. Every time a pulse is received a bean will be dropped and it will land in one of the seven slots of the machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescomb</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/rescomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/rescomb/</guid>
      <description>Rescomb is a resonant Comb filter. A comb filter is a special kind of filter that creates multiple spaced notches. This module provides an CV input which is tuned (1V/octave) and a feedback parameter. when the feedback is high it will resonate enhancing the frequencies of the comb.
This is the first module that I designed for VCV Rack. I really like Comb filters, so I coded in Vult a very simple version after playing with it and tweaking parameters I got this version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescomb2</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/rescomb2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/rescomb2/</guid>
      <description>Rescomb 2 is a simple but effective comb filter that can be used to create metallic and glitchy sounds. Thanks to it&amp;rsquo;s high feedback and input distortion it can be used to mangle the sound in extreme ways.
Rescomb 2 can be used as well as a Karplus-Strong like sound generator by using it&amp;rsquo;s direct V/OCT input and stimulating it with short pulses.
Documentation Filter Section The knobs Frequency, Feedback and Drive provide a pair of inputs and attenuverters that can be used to modulate the parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/send/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/send/</guid>
      <description>Send (or Util-Send) provides the send/return functionality found in most mixers but for a single stereo channel. Just connect you audio to the inputs and take from the outputs. Connect your effect from the send jacks and connect it back in the return jacks.
Documentation  Blend: controls the mix between the unprocessed and processed signals. Includes an input modulation with attenuverter. Send (jacks): provides the audio signal to connect to you audio processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slap</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/slap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/slap/</guid>
      <description>Slap is an envelope based on the electrical circuit I found in a book of electronics for music. Slap has the same hitting nature of Spank. The module includes a VCA so you can use it directly to control an input source.
Documentation Each of the following controls provides an attenuverter and a CV input to modulate them.
 Attack: rising rate of the envelope. Decay: decaying rate until the signal reaches the Sustain value .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spank</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/spank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/spank/</guid>
      <description>Spank is the envelope generator in charge of producing the snappy sounds of Trummor and Trummor 2. All transitions are exponential since they are modeled after the behavior of an analog envelope. The module includes a VCA so you can use it directly to control an input source.
Documentation Each of the knobs provides an attenuverter and a CV input to modulate them.
 Attack: rising rate of the envelope. Hold: time that the envelope stays in the maximum output (10 V).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splie</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/splie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/splie/</guid>
      <description>Splie is an utility module that I made because it was handy when developing my modules. It provides a buffered input that can be distributed to other modules. This is very handy when one wants to change only one patch cable and distribute the signal to many other modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stabile</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/stabile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/stabile/</guid>
      <description>Stabile is a state variable filter. It provides LP, HP, and BP filters. Additionally to the three filter outputs it provides an extra output imitates the behavior of the SEM filter.
The story of this filter goes even before the existence of Vult. I implemented the initial version of this filter in a microcontroller. With the years I have made many tweaks an simplifications. In fact this filter is very efficient and the sound is very effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tohe</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/tohe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/tohe/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes one needs just a gentle change to the sound in order to make it fit better. Tohe is a tone control that balances the high and low
Documentation  Tone: controls the internal filters. Full left you&amp;rsquo;ll get a bass sound. Full right cuts the bass and enhances the treble. Input: signal to be processed. Output: processed signal.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trummor</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/trummor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/trummor/</guid>
      <description>Trummor is a drum synthesizer that produces 909 style kicks. Trummor can be used to produce other type of percusive sounds like toms and simple snares or hats.
I started developing the algorithms behind Trummor a long time ago and I made a simplified hardware version of it. When VCV Rack came out, I adapted the code and started expanding the sonic capabilities.
Trummor has been replaced by Trummor 2 which is an improved version with even more sonic capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trummor 2</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/trummor2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/trummor2/</guid>
      <description>Trummor 2 is the evolution of Trummor that was designed with the idea of expanding the sonic capabilities of Trummor.
It was designed based on the input of many members of the VCV Rack community specially Alejandro Galán Álvaro who participated in most of the stages. Trummor 2 is, in his words:
&amp;ldquo;a powerhouse of drum sounds. FM drums, metalic claps, analog-style kicks, all sorts of resonated karplus-strong style strings, blips and blops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unstabile</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/unstabile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/unstabile/</guid>
      <description>Unstabile is &amp;ldquo;circuit bent&amp;rdquo; version of Stabile. When making Stabile I aimed to have a ver efficient and smooth filter that I could run in a small ARM processor. To achieve that I left out many things from the original circuit. With Unstabile remade the model and introduced nonlinearities that can occur when the circuit is fed with low voltage. The result is Unstabile a filter that makes everything sound big and distorted&amp;hellip; and it can self-oscillate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vessek</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vessek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vessek/</guid>
      <description>Vessek is an oscillator for people looking for analog sound.
Vessek started modeling the basic circuit of an analog saw wave oscillator. Most of the parameters were initially obtained from my compact analog bass synth. I got a pretty good matching of the sound that I bet it would pass a blind test. Later in the development, samples of other well known analog oscillators were sent to me by members of the VCV Rack community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolv</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/wolv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 22:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/wolv/</guid>
      <description>Wolv is a very special wave shaper/folder capable of producing a wide range of sounds out of basic waveforms. It is a model of the hardware module with the same name: https://www.vult-dsp.com/wolv
The design is based on the original design by Ian Fritz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangents</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/tangents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 11:54:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/tangents/</guid>
      <description>Tangents is a filter based on the Steiner-Parker structure. One big addition I made in this version compared with the hardware version is that this module leaves exposed three inputs (LP, BP and HP). This makes possible to connect three sources and affecting the frequency content for each input differently.
The paid version of Tangents has 3 different implementations. Each implementation is based on a different simulation model I developed. The original Tangents was based on the Steiner-Parker design by Yves Usson version (YuSynth).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vorg</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 11:54:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vorg/</guid>
      <description>Vorg is a low/high pass filter based on a modernized Operational Transconductance Amplifier version of the MS-20 filter. Vorg is the first module that I developed with the idea of making it feel exactly as a real eurorack module. This considers the spacing between the knobs and sizes. Vorg is also part of Freak. Using it with Freak allows modulating the Resonance and Drive controls.
Documentation  Cutoff: Defines the frequency at which the filters starts attenuating frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vortex</title>
      <link>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 11:54:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modlfo.github.io/VultModules/vortex/</guid>
      <description>Vortex is filter based on a famous russian design. The filter is a Low pass and Band pass capable of self-oscillating. Vortex is a detailed simulation of the original circuit with a few small tweaks to give my personal touch.
Vortex is part of the Premium package that can be purchased through the VCV store.
Documentation  Cutoff: this is the main knob in a filter. It defines the frequency at which the filter starts taking action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
